Manas Ranjan Satapathy

manasranjansatapathy96@gmail.com

Software Developer

linkedin/ManasRanjan Github/ManasRanjan

Portfolio: ManasRanjanSatapathy

Objective: Having 2 Years of experience in Software development, my aim is to find an exciting and challenging entry level position in the IT Industry alongside a company who will continuously motivate and drive me to do my best and improve on my skills and abilities in order to be able to assist the company in achieving its mission and goals. I am an excellent team worker.

EDUCATION

Phone: 7978237226

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, GIET University, Gunupur, CGPA: 9.07/10.00

August 2019 — April 2023

Board of Secondary Education, Odisha (12TH), SSVM, Neelakantha Nagar, Berhampur, Percentage: 81.33 July 2016 — June 2018

Higher Secondary Education, Odisha (10TH), SSVM, Neelakantha Nagar, Berhampur, Percentage: 92

July 2015 — June 2016

PROJECTS

Used Car Sales Portal (Work In Progress) (Github)

- Developed a Microservices and Micro-Frontend based application in which a user can sell his/her used car and can also buy cars which has been posted by others for sale.
- Implemented concepts like Feign client, eureka naming server, Load balancing, API Gateways, and Fault Tolerance. I have used Technologies like Java, spring cloud, spring boot, JWT authentication and authorization, Microservices, Micro-Frontend, React, SQL API Gateway, and Tailwind CSS

To-do List (Github)

• Built this project to keep track of tasks that need to be done. This application will act like a task keeper where the user would be able to enter the tasks that they need to do. Once they are done with their tasks they can also remove them from the list. They can also edit the entered Tasks. **Tech:** Spring Boot, JSP, JPA, Java

E-Commerce Website (Github)

 Built an E-Commerce Website where user can buy products and admin can add and remove products. Tech: Java, Spring Boot, React, SQL

Walmart Sales Forecasting (Github)

 We have built a machine learning model which will predict the sales of a company for the coming holidays based on the previous trends. User could get an overall idea about the number of employees they need in that period. Tech: Python and Machine Learning

Note Taker (Github)

• Developed a Web application where we can store, update, delete and view our Notes. Here we have focused mainly on the concepts of Hibernate. We have also used HTML, CSS and JavaScript to design this page. **Tech:** Java, JDBC, Servlet, Hibernate, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

July 2023 - Present

Amiti Software Technologies Private Limited

Bangalore

- I am working as a junior software developer in which we are providing end to end solution for vehicle remarketing for automobile companies in Canada/USA/Europe such as GMF, VW, BMW, Honda, Chevrolet, Porsche, Ford and Toyota.
- Technologies Used: ASP DOTNET Core, Spring boot, Microservices, Micro-Frontends, React, GIT, SQL, Xunit

Advanced Robotic Process Automation (Intern)

June 2022 – May 2023

Bhubaneswar

• I interned in Advanced Robotic Process Automation, where I developed features to automate the order-to-cash cycle by efficiently scraping and integrating data from diverse sources.

• Technologies Used: Java, SQL, Hibernate, Postman, OOPs concept, JDBC, Servlet, Selenium, Git, spring

SKILLS

Highradius

Languages JAVA, JAVASCRIPT

Database SQL

Frameworks & Libraries Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring, React, Hibernate, DOT NET, JSP, Junit, XUnit, Mockito

Others Data Structures And Algorithms, OOPS Concept, Microservices, Selenium, Postman, REST, GIT, JPA

AWARDS & HONORS

- · Spring Boot 3 in 100 Steps(Udemy), Highway to HighRadius Internship, Machine Learning using Python
- · Global rank of 17k in GFG for problem Solving, SQL(Intermediate) certificate on Hackerrank
- SQL(Basic) certificate on Hackerrank, Python(Basic) certificate on Hackerrank, Learn Java (Great Learning)